♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ ♪ but his bosses
didn't like him
♪ so they shot him
into space ♪ ♪
♪ we'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst we can find ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ and we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
- ♪ robot roll call ♪
- all right, let's go!
- ♪ Cambot! ♪
- Pan left!
- ♪ Gypsy! ♪
- Hi, girl!
- ♪ Tom servo! ♪
- What a cool guy!
- ♪ Crow...! ♪
- He's a wisecracker.
♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
♪ and other science facts ♪
♪ la la la ♪
♪ then repeat to yourself ♪
♪ "it's just a show,
I should really just relax" ♪
♪ for "mystery science
theater 3000!" ♪
[Whooshing, creaking,
whirring, clanking]
Hey, hey, hello, welcome
to the satellite of love.
I'm Joel, these are my robots
and, uh, you know,
it's baseball season
up here on
the satellite of love,
and in space that means
one thing-- Milwaukee.
I mean tee-ball.
Commercial sign in 15 seconds.
All right, crow,
I want you to go long.
Come on, buddy, way out there,
buddy, way out there.
Joel, Joel, is this gonna hurt?
Are you sure
it's not gonna hurt?
Quit being such a pantywaist.
Just hold still
and nothing will get hurt.
[All cheer, glass breaks,
air whooshing]
[All screaming]
We'll be right back, I hope!
♪♪
[All screaming, air whooshing]
[Whooshing stops]
Oh, thanks, gypsy, you patched
up the hole, thanks a lot.
I thought I told you kids
not to play ball in the house!
- Oh, we're sorry.
- Sorry, gypsy.
We're sorry, we won't do it ag--
the coast is clear.
Crow, go long, buddy.
All right.
All right, buddy,
this one's coming out to you.
Shag it long, Joel,
shag it long.
Go way long, way long-- okay.
I'm open, I'm open!
Ow, ow, ow!
I caught it!
- Yes, yes!
- [Cheering]
All right, all right, excellent!
Another triumph
of the human spirit!
Uh-oh, you guys--
I caught it--
I knew reading that George will
book would pay off.
Hey, the mad steinbrenners
are calling
and you're losing your glove.
Yes, yes, yes!
Dr. Forrester, let's do
the wave-- whoo... oh!
Stop playing around up there
and get to the invention
exchange, Van lingle mungo.
Hey, nice mug!
Oh, okay, sirs, I can show you
my invention exchange.
This is my new invention--
it's called the cellulite phone.
It reminds people
that they should stop dialing
and start dieting.
And that's not all--
the cellulite phone features
a speed-dialing system
that puts you directly in touch
with Richard Simmons.
[Imitating Simmons]
You know, when you were carrying
around all that weight
and the kids used to show movies
on your shirt and you were
so unhappy and--
[crying]
Use deal-a-meal and--
and the cellulite phone gently
reminds you what could happen
if you order out
for the wrong kind of food.
Uh, hello, domino's, yeah,
I'm here with, uh, a couple
of friends, a group of friends,
and we'd like to order
your large pizza, yeah,
and I'd also like that
with extra breakfast cereal
and some fruit bats--
no olives.
--And some a-1 sauce
on top of that--
and for traveling, the cellulite
phone can be stored in, um,
this special pink nylon
stretch pants carrying case.
What do you think, sirs?
We don't have time
for that kind of nonsense.
Frank and I have started
our own gizmonic daycare center
here at deep 13,
and frank's developed
a new baby formula that's going
to be very lucrative for us.
Isn't that right, frank?
Oh, that's right, I just fed
this little fella here
something I like to call
"miracle baby growth
wonder formula."
It helps build strong bodies
in 12 ways.
[Baby crying]
Oh, yes, you love me,
that's right.
Here, that's okay...
Oh, never mind.
Look, booby,
your experiment this week
is called "time of the apes"
and it's really immature.
We asked all the kids here
and they said it--
[explosion]
I did it!
It worked better than I thought!
I'm the dad, I'm the dad!
Tell me--
[Alarm blaring]
[All]
Movie sign! Movie sign!
[Clanking, whirring,
creaking, whooshing]
♪♪
Oh, no,
it's a Sandy frank thing.
[All]
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank ♪
♪ here we go again ♪♪
- Hey!
- ♪ Sandy... ♪
Neat! Looks like
a "sesame street" segment.
It does, doesn't it?
I'll take the kazue takita,
but hold on the norobu there.
[All]
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank ♪
♪ these things
aren't in the film ♪♪
"Help me! Help me!
I'm trapped in this copyright,
I wanna live, I wanna live!"
[Slow guitar music]
Ooh, more sedate.
Original story by sasquatch,
adapted from a play by koko
and a novel by chuckles.
Hey, they look like
they're on a playground--
they must be "recess" monkeys.
- Doh!
- I will pull off that arm...
Don't hurt me.
I love the tender love theme
from "time of the apes."
Isaac Asimov?
"What are you looking at?"
Hey, where's b.J.?
Oh...
♪♪
I don't know why I kept
duplicates of this shot.
Who took these photos anyway,
Diane arbus?
Huh?
[Whistling bird call]
I'm starving.
"For attention."
"Butter, mmm..."
--So don't disturb their work.
I won't, mother.
"And don't dub
with your mouth full!"
Johnny, you know
your uncle Charley has made
some major discoveries.
You should be proud of him.
"He discovered you're Japanese."
[Doorbell rings]
That's Caroline.
Hurry, it's time to go.
[All]
Say... she's-- oh...
For crying out loud.
- Okay, I'm ready.
- Hello, Caroline.
- Good morning.
- Hello, dear.
Johnny, you look after
Caroline today.
I will, dad.
"Oh! What was in that oatmeal?"
A tremor.
No...
Johnny, don't go,
it's too dangerous.
I don't care.
Come on, Caroline.
"Off to meet my doom, mom,
see you after school."
Enjoy yourselves.
♪ ...holiday with Johnny ♪
♪ every day's a holiday-- ♪
Hey, it's jame gumb's Van.
[Lisping]
It puts the lotion on its skin.
I think that's cute.
Good morning, children.
We're not too late, are we?
"Oh, we hit her."
- Good morning.
- Hello.
At the moment we're doing
some experiments on cold sleep.
[Caroline]
Cold sleep?
Yes, we're trying to preserve
various creatures
for extended periods.
Hiya, Fred.
Hi, Sally.
Bye.
And are they still alive?
Oh, yes, they awaken
when we thaw them out.
That's incredible.
What's in here, Catherine?
In this room
we have some monkeys.
Surprise! That's where the title
of the film came from.
Actually, he was asleep for over
20 years until this morning.
"Now he's graduated
from college"
we call that one king Kong.
'Cause he's so small, get it?
[Laughing sarcastically]
[Beeping and clicking]
Oh, it's fantastic!
It sure is.
It's cardboard.
Is this the control center?
Well, it's about time.
It's about space--
[Humming]
Good morning, Caroline.
Look at the mountain.
We had a warning from the
seismological institute today.
There's seems to be
some subterranean shifting.
You mean an earthquake.
It looks serious--
maybe an earthquake.
Yes, but nothing'll
happen suddenly.
[All scream]
Well, Caroline,
is it interesting?
Oh, yes, especially
the cold sleep experiment.
Dr. Lee, the children are very
concerned about our monkeys.
Yes, you get the feeling
they're really dead.
Are you sure they'll live again?
Why, of course they will.
Come, I'll show you
something fascinating.
For a change.
Hmm...
"I love you, Margaret."
"Frank, not now!"
♪♪
Seems like a lot of work
to go through to make
an eggo frozen waffle.
"Play 'misty' for me."
[Click, distorted sounds]
Radio shack parts.
Kitty!
It's snowball!
Hostess snowball--
[Chuckles]
Hmm, somebody's carpet.
And it's being steam-cleaned.
Rug doctor--
steamin' mad at monkeys.
[Crackling]
Yech--
[sniffs]
Oh, they cauterized her.
Eww...
They're using
grecian formula-- neat.
[Whoosh]
Ooh, good god a-monkey!
"A little horse
for a little monkey."
Hey, he'll have himself
on his back.
[Beeping and clicking]
"Hmm, my stocks are up."
Ah...
"Aw, shoot, am I tired, oh..."
"Now to shave his butt
and put cosmetics on it."
"Oh, I'm not good until I get
a cup of coffee, can you--"
- oh, he's alive!
- Yes!
There, as good as new.
"And no freezer burn."
Is it all right?
The freezing didn't hurt it?
No, he was only sleeping.
It's William burroughs.
We could have left him frozen
for a hundred years--
or even a thousand--
without causing him any damage.
You see, with our new process--
[snoring and whistling]
We can preserve life
almost eternally.
"Go ahead, bite him."
We've even experimented
with human beings.
Really? Human beings?
"Yes-- this is Walt Disney."
We have here a very wealthy man,
James bedford.
In his will, he requested
that his body be frozen
immediately after death.
We gave him various compounds
to reverse the decaying effects
of old age.
"Yeah, we turned him
into a hummel-- check it out."
--At 196 degrees below zero.
And so we hope
that when he awakens,
he'll be even younger
and healthier than before.
It seems wrong to tamper
with the laws of nature.
"Hey, I know."
- Here.
- [Gasping]
This room is for
very special experiments.
Johnny, don't touch
any of the equipment.
"I don't care."
This capsule is used
for people, right?
And they're frozen in there?
Once they're inside, all the
controls are set for our test
and a computer takes over
automatically.
"It's glorious."
We transmit our findings to
the world's leading scientists.
But when they're frozen at
hundreds of degrees below zero,
it's just like they're
really dead.
- Yes.
- Only they're not.
"But their souls are."
Don't they feel anything?
[Squeaking]
We first prepare them
with a special injection
like an anesthetic.
"Want some?"
And then it's like
they're sleeping.
Some even tell us
that they were dreaming.
"Of a white Christmas?"
It's really incredible.
Johnny, don't go in there.
"I don't care."
Come on out.
We haven't completed
those experiments.
I just wonder what it's like
to be frozen.
Now get out--
or I'll get very angry.
[Boom]
"See?"
An earthquake!
- Uh-oh!
- Whoa!
Oh... Nelly! Oops.
Johnny, get out!
Johnny! Johnny!
"Johnny, be good... aah...!"
Go, Johnny, go!
Oh, the people upstairs
are dancing again.
Oh, for crying out loud.
Rockin' and a-- rollin'.
Get in here!
"It keeps the hot side hot
and the cold side cold!"
"How do it know?"
(Gasping)
- Whoa...
- Whoa!
Krakatoa!
Oh, no, it hit
the plot contrivance switch!
"Oh, wow..."
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
They're gonna end up being
an irwin Allen production.
- Mm-hmm.
- Here we go.
I love the sound
of breaking glass.
- Especially when I'm lonely.
- Yeah.
Oh, but I hate
these Minnesota winters.
Lookit-- they're shellacked,
then decoupaged,
then sold at an art store.
Neat.
Hmm.
If a tree falls in Japan
and no one is there--
Johnny's Carson's Malibu home.
- Not anymore.
- Sorry, Johnny.
Did the earth move
for you too?
No, but the model did.
You know, I bet Johnny
cares now, huh, fellas?
[All chuckling]
I feel the plot move
under my feet.
Whoa!
I was at a party
like this once, you know.
Whoa, suddenly
we're at the Fillmore!
Oh, boy, it's the credits again!
No...!
♪♪
Do not attempt
to adjust your TV set.
Wow, she's got
freeze-proof mascara.
"Whoa, I really tied one on
last night.
I got the sake goggles
big-time."
It's the daleks!
Exterminate,
exterminate, exter--
where are we?
Uncle!
Does that mean give up?
The earthquake...
[Gasps]
It's just a door.
What a pantywaist, geez.
How strange.
Uncle Charley!
[Imitating William demarest]
Ah, what do you want, kid?
Chip, Ernie-- where the heck
is Preston sturges?
It doesn't look like
the institute.
"The one that I was
committed to."
What happened to my uncle?
What happened to your pants?
Hello?
- ♪ Hello... ♪
- ♪ hello... ♪
[All]
Hello!
What now?
[Dramatic music]
Let's go ahead.
[Imitates dramatic music]
"Hey, opened it--"
uncle!
Not!
[All gasp]
- "Do I worry you?"
- "Love me!"
"Hi, how are ya?"
[Imitates Woody Allen]
"Oh, I got my hand on the door
and it's stuck
and I'm frightened and-- ho..."
[Screams]
[Alarm blaring]
"Human alert!"
"Human!"
"Ah!"
It's a whole planet
of Ron perlmans! Whoa...
Look there!
[Caroline screams]
"Make my day!"
Ah, you-- you let us go
or I'll kill you!
Johnny, stop that!
"Don't talk to monkeys, Johnny."
Where are we?
You're tied to a tree.
Where's my uncle Charley?
I don't know, Johnny.
It's all so strange.
Catherine, I'm scared!
It's like a de palma film.
Don't be afraid, we're with you.
"We're doomed but with you."
Why are there only apes here?
Ooh, I'm getting dizzy.
Why aren't there
any human beings?
Read the book.
"Do you like
long walks on the beach?
Chinese foods?
Mushing up your bananas?"
"I could do wonders
with this hair, you realize."
Catherine, I'm scared!
We have to try and stay calm,
Caroline, understand?
"If they eat us now,
they'll be hungry in an hour."
Oh-- [spits]
Oh, good thing
he suddenly evolved.
Hey, here comes
the scopes monkey trial guy.
Ooh-- psychedelic.
"Oh, why, I oughta--
oh, you're not worth it, oh--"
Neat.
[As George c. Scott's patton]
"Now, you magnificent
son of bitch--"
[trumpet fanfare]
[Squealing]
Oh, what are they
gonna do with us?
"I hope they lower your voice."
It looks like they're gonna
take us somewhere.
The company picnic?
They're gonna kill us!
No! I don't wanna be killed
by a monkey!
"I wanna die at my own hand!"
We mustn't do
anything to anger them.
[Lisping]
"Come on, girls, we're gonna
give 'em a makeover
they won't believe."
[Tom servo chuckling]
"She's first."
Mystery guest,
enter and sign in, please.
Make her walk the plank,
you salty dog.
"Slag heap," rated "r".
[Distorted guitar music]
Today on
"involuntary cliff diving,"
we've got three contestants.
They've entered the valley
of the fuzz-tone guitar.
Ooh...
[All gasping]
"A bowling ball!"
They're human bones!
They're gonna kill us!
No!
"I don't care--
maybe just a little."
"I like you--
I'm gonna kill you last."
[All gasp]
"So, we put up with centuries
of bellhop costumes,
"little t-shirts
that say 'zippy' on them,
"badminton on ice, roller
skates, cigars in our mouths...
Lancelot link alone set us back
a hundred years!"
[Imitates spurs jingling]
"Now you!"
Let's run, Catherine!
Whoa!
"Run for it!"
[Gunfire]
- "Serpentine!"
- "serpentine!"
- "Serpentine!
Dodge the bullets!"
Ooh!
Oh-- meanwhile,
in the emerald forest...
Where's John boorman?
Don't let them get away!
Kill them!
Good plan.
[Twangy music]
I love the jaw harp.
After them!
Where'd they go?
This way!
Oh, look up there-- ned beatty!
"You're a fat old hog, heh-heh."
Sorry.
Ah!
There's a bridge there!
Nice bridgework.
Let's try and cross it, come on!
But stay together.
Yeah, that's what
al green said-- I agree.
- I hear ya.
- Yeah.
- "Whoa!"
- "whoa!"
Did you see them?
They disappeared!
Come on, this way!
"Let's have our picnic
over here!"
"Prepare to meet Kali--
in hell!"
You know,
it's good to have thumbs.
Yeah-- huh?
Where did that come from?
I don't know.
You said "bowling ball" earlier.
What did that mean?
I don't know, it's just---
that's it,
just a little more to go.
"Must... get to...
My utility belt."
- "Morning, Ron."
- "Hi, Phil."
- "How's the wife?"
- "Good, thanks for asking."
"Say, nice boots
you're wearing there."
[Gasping]
[British accent]
Look, if you can't work out
30 minutes a day,
you don't deserve a hot date.
Sheena crow.
[Gasps]
"My piece of wood!
It died so that we might live."
- "Oh, it's just
some kids down there."
- "Oh."
Did you see them?
"I can't see anything
through this mask."
We couldn't find them anywhere.
They must have crossed
to the other side.
This way, this way.
"So let's just hang here
for a while."
"Oof-- aren't you glad
you use dial?"
Tickle, tickle.
"Don't you wish everybody did?"
That was lucky.
Nobody saw us-- keep going.
Tickle, tickle.
That's mean, Joel.
Hey, hey, it's Ken kesey
and the merry pranksters!
"Dang tourists."
Let's go, this way!
Oh, like you know
where you're going.
Ah, a house!
Look, there's a house!
[Squeaky]
Yes!
Must you scream
every observation?
Careful-- we don't know
who lives there.
[Gravelly voice]
"Hi, I'm William Conrad
for first alert.
"Don't let this happen to you.
"Paper windows just aren't safe.
"Uh, use the door.
Thank you."
There's no one inside.
"Time for your origami lessons."
[Suspenseful music]
[Imitates music]
"Hey, let's find a refrigerator
and freeze ourselves back!"
"It's roomy-- I like it."
Don't make any noise.
Shh...
Hey, Keith Richards at home.
[Ape squeals]
No, don't--
oh, naked apes!
- No, don't!
- No, no!
It's a monkey mime!
"Hi."
Hey, you caught him right
in the middle of his facial.
Is this your home?
Yes.
Ah! It speaks!
I hope it's all right,
our entering like this.
I don't mind.
Yeah, now tell him
about the torn window.
Yeah--
♪ you're gonna get
in trouble-- ♪
[Apes yelling outside,
Catherine gasps]
This way!
Over here!
Catherine!
Here! Let's run!
[Whooshing, creaking,
whirring, clanking]
Johnny, don't go,
it's too dangerous.
I don't care.
"Why doesn't Johnny care?"
A film by bell labs.
[Crow imitating projector]
Johnny likes to sit next to
his girlfriend Sally
here on the bus,
but she's got other fish to fry.
Strike one against Johnny.
Hey, that building up ahead
is Johnny's school,
tarkus brainlab 4,
and here is Johnny's
inner sanctum helpmate,
Mrs. Reese.
To Johnny, the halls of tarkus
brainlab 4 are filled with
dark, shadowy figures.
A few whispered words,
the sting of a needle
and they're gone, gone, gone.
No one stays too long
in Johnny's world-- would you?
What looks like a normal
playground to you or I
takes on a hideous simian
appearance in Johnny's mind.
Images leap and dance like
melting colored caramel candies.
[Distorting voice]
Johnny's heroine is on loan from
the Bobby goldsboro institute--
from the snide museum.
[Projector imitation continues]
Here in Johnny's fun lab, he can
manipulate objects at will
and no one dares to stop him.
Johnny concentrates hard
to make the hurting stop.
Here's blue director 4,
Dr. Todd ambrosius,
Johnny's real dad.
Uh-oh, time for
a heart-to-heart, Johnny.
You see, it's all because
Johnny doesn't care.
Do you care?
Because a mind like Johnny's
is a terrible thing to unleash.
I'm Tom servo announcing
for bell laboratories.
Good night and commercial sign--
[Click]
♪♪
What do we do?!
They're all around the house!
There's a back door there!
Thank you.
That was fun, huh?
Now we know
why Johnny doesn't care.
There's a knife! Hurry!
Ooh, they saved the shoes.
"What did they want?"
[Staccato music]
♪ Tradition... ♪
Tradition!
After them, after them!
No, no, forget the beach chair,
you're in a hurry!
[Gasps]
[Apes muttering]
Statute of limitations.
It looks like they're scared.
Yes, you're right.
Picasso?!
[Apes muttering nervously]
They're afraid of that shrine!
They're afraid of tripe?
No, "shrine," shrine.
Oh.
Looks like tripe though,
doesn't it?
Come on, run, try and move
faster than the plot.
[Apes exclaiming fearfully]
[Phone ringing]
Hey, the cheese phone
is ringing.
Yes, Mr. Colby.
Member on line 2.
It's me-- gebar.
What's that?
They went towards
green mountain?
Very well, I'll be right there.
Oscar wilde? Hmm?
Don't worry, sir,
they'll be caught soon.
This is a very serious
situation.
They must never be allowed
to cross the border
and enter green mountain!
Smoking a cigar...
We must call out all our troops.
Was that bonzo the magician?
I'll get them before they
reach the frontier.
"Uh, give me Davy crocket,
king of the wild frontier--
thank you."
This is the district leader.
We must have reinforcements.
"I resent him."
Oh, Johnny, are you all right?
"I don't care."
We must keep going!
♪ I cannot stay,
I must be going... ♪
[Birds screeching]
♪ 99 banana daiquiris on
the wall, 99 banana daiquiris ♪
[Humming tune]
Hold it!
Ho, ho, ho, hold the bus!
It's the banana splits show!
Fleegle, dreegle,
drooper and snork!
About face!
"Uh-oh, it's prince!
His royal purpleness!"
Those invaders must be caught!
And this time you mustn't
let them get away or I'll
have you all shot!
It is prince.
We understand, sir, but no one
wants to go into green mountain.
You cowards!
Those invaders must never be
allowed to cross the border
into green mountain-- get going!
Yes, sir! Forward!
And get them!
"A birthday present--
I like them."
Run through the jungle.
[Gasps]
Barbed-wire fences!
"I don't care."
[Suspenseful music]
[Imitating music]
Green mountain.
Whoa, high-grade weed!
- Cool! Sinse!
- Ooh!
We can't stay here like this.
I wonder why the fence is here.
There must be a way around.
To make good neighbors.
"Okay, size, place, get a buddy!
Pair off."
"Let's dig to China."
They're getting close!
"I found a truffle!"
Go on, hurry through!
Go on and keep your head down--
"in shame."
They went thataway.
[Creaking]
[ Catherine gasps]
Johnny, watch out!
"I don't care, I don't care,
I don't care, I don't care,
I don't care!"
Bet you care now, don't ya?
Are you all right, Johnny?
You're not hurt?
It's some kind of a trap.
It's designed to kill
anyone who enters here.
No...
[Leaves rustling]
Oh, oh, the tree's
having a seizure!
Ah-choo!
Come on!
"Ragweed-- aah...!"
Oop, saw that coming.
"Ooh, fresh coconuts, aah...!"
Oh, they got a lovely bunch.
"I'm allergic to it."
Oh, Catherine...!
You mustn't cry.
With this knife,
I'm not scared of anyone.
Well, you're dumber
than those rocks, kid.
Hurry, hurry!
Don't leave me!
[Whoosh]
Help me, help me, Catherine!
Oh, now that's fun.
Caroline!
Help, help!
In the bag.
Stay calm, Caroline.
I'll climb up and get you!
Hey, I got a great, kooky idea:
Let's pretend she's a piñata.
Olé!
You'll be all right!
Or not.
A little more!
[Twig snaps, Catherine gasps]
Huh?
Steven seagal
in "shoot the monkey."
Oh...
Catherine!
"What? What?"
It's Mike nesmith!
He was a monkee, true.
[Rumbling dramatic music]
That's me on the bass there.
"Nice... gun."
You're human, aren't you?
She's very discriminating.
You are-- a human?
Are you a human?
Yes, I am-- we all are.
"And we're little kids!"
Hey, just like ed ames
on "the tonight show."
Catherine!
♪♪
We met a nice guy at last.
The apes aren't the only ones
here, right, Catherine?
"Damn, we got us a family!"
--Afraid to follow us here.
I got it--
the apes didn't set the traps.
He did it-- didn't you?
"Maybe."
How did you get to this country?
"Our mom dropped us off."
Well, uh, you see--
oh, I have so many things
to ask you.
We came here
in a very strange way.
"By refrigerator."
Where are we?
What is this place?
"Love me!"
You're on green mountain.
This is green mountain?
"Are you a Hatfield or a McCoy?"
Have you found them?
Not a trace.
This way-- they must be near.
"Let's crap in our hands
and throw it at people.
It doesn't matter how you
evolve, it's still damn funny."
Look!
"There's some now."
Headquarters, headquarters.
This is police chief gebar--
what is it?
- "I can't move my lips!"
- The barbed wire has been cut!
They must have
crossed the border!
- Idiots!
- "Who hired them?"
How did they get away from you?
This means they'll join forces
with godo!
Go-go?
You must find them!
Gordo?
"Well, it's not much,
but it's close to the bus lines
and I kinda live here
during the off years."
"You can make fire?"
Oh...
Is this where you live?
"No, it's my summer home--
what do you think?"
I was born here.
Geez.
Oh-- do you, do you live here
with your parents?
"No, they're dead--
dead, dead!"
No-- they died a long time ago.
Oh, you're right.
You lived here all alone?
Then you had no one to look
after you when you were sick.
"Oh, rub it in, kid."
Then why don't you join us?
Leave the mountain with us.
- "Join us..."
- No, it's much safer here.
"Join us..."
And this is my home.
Come with us.
Look, water!
Johnny!
It's all right.
That Johnny
is a walking faux pas.
"Gulp, gulp-- burp."
Mmm, tastes good-- here.
My name is Johnny.
"Yeah, like I care--
who's your sister?"
This is Catherine,
she works with my uncle.
"As a geisha."
And this is my sister Caroline.
"She'll drink anything."
My name is godo.
Godo?
A funny name.
"Yeah? Well, bite me, kid."
All the apes seem to be
afraid of you.
Godo, I was just thinking.
If you say
that you were born here,
then this country is not
inhabited only by apes.
"Well, there's me too."
And there must be other humans
here near the mountain,
don't you think so?
Um, I don't know.
Don't you remember
any other people living here?
"Should I shave my mustache?"
Some boombas.
Boombox?
What did you say?
I don't remember.
Oh, no short-term memory, huh?
I think we ought to take care
of Caroline's wound.
"She doesn't have one"
"well, let's give her one."
Those clothes are very torn.
"They're going to have to
come off."
[Snickering]
We have to find
something for you.
I'll look around.
♪♪
Faster, faster, go on!
Go on or I'll kill you!
Oh, there goes sheriff lobo!
[Goofy laughter]
Right on his head.
Forward! I said forward!
You cowards!
"Uh, could you take
a little off the sides,
like what he's got, yeah."
"More, more-- thank you, sir."
That'll teach you to disobey me!
Is there anyone else who refuses
to follow my orders?
"Yoo-hoo down here-- I need
some discipline-- yoo-hoo!
Nuts, he didn't hear me."
Faster, faster!
Hey, Steve Tyler from aerosmith.
Look, there he is.
Come on!
"Bring along those
furnace doors back there."
"Man, it's starting to smell
like a zoo around here!"
Why are you stopping?
Keep going, keep going!
Uh, yes, sir.
"S-Sorry, sarge."
You, that way!
The others follow me!
"I want a taste of that whip."
Oh, the mime is back.
Oh, great,
it's a planet of owls.
And they are not what they seem.
- Mm-mm.
- Get it?
I heard one call my name.
Eddie munster!
Yeah!
"The invaders," in color.
Hmm? What the heck was that?
"Corn Dodgers! I love 'em!"
[Chuckling]
"What a pig!"
It's delicious, isn't it?
[Burp]
"Yup!"
Strange food.
You like it?
Oh, he shaved
the back of his hands too.
Do I look more civilized now?
"No."
What's this--
it's a funny-looking vegetable.
Yes.
It tastes good, hmm?
It tastes like mashed potatoes.
[Sarcastic laughter]
What is it, pepe?
Godo, the ape troops
are coming here!
They've set fire
to the mountain!
What?
"Oh, that's great, but--
who are you?!"
Don't move from here!
[Johnny]
Pepe, what is godo like?
He's strong and very clever.
"And a snappy dresser."
How did you make friends
with godo?
A long time ago, I came
to this mountain just to play.
Then my mother came looking for
me but she was caught in a trap.
"An ooey-gooey snappy trap."
And then godo came
and rescued you, right?
Yes, that's why I love godo.
"I love him too,
my little friend."
♪♪
Start another fire there,
hurry, hurry!
There's godo!
Kill him, kill him!
Go, go, godo,
watch him go, go, go.
Godo, godo, watch him
go, go, go.
No, no, godo will kill us--
no, no!
Kill him! Kill him!
Hey, you could kill him
by shooting him.
"Use the guns!"
Kill godo!
Shoot him, shoot him!
Fire!
[Dramatic trumpet music]
It's really hard to draw a bead
through those masks, you know.
This music sounds like it's from
"sketches of Spain."
Or "sketches of spam!"
[Chuckling]
[All coughing]
[Imitating art fern]
"Ooh, that's good weed--
mm-hmm... oh-ho!"
The smoke's too thick,
we can't stay here!
Let's go-- hurry, hurry!
"Out here where the plot
is thinner!"
[Gunfire]
Nicolas cage in "wild at heart."
Godo!
Godo, help!
Go to hell?
Hey, he feeds you,
he takes you into his home
and that's the thanks--
no, "godo, help."
--Needs your help,
and Catherine's hurt too!
[All imitate panting]
Catherine, hold on!
Oh, godo, pepe is--
pepe, don't move!
Pepe, don't be a hero!
No, don't come here--
run, run-- aah!
Pepe! Godo!
- Godo!
- Pepe!
Are you all right?
- Godo!
He's a crispy critter, kid.
Mm-hmm... imagine what that fur
smells like burning?
Whoo-hoo...
"Wow, there was a bear
with ranger hat on
and he kept screaming,
'only you--'"
pepe!
Give me your hand!
I've got it!
Ooh, that's not my hand!
Hey, Joel, he's got a monkey
on his back.
I hear ya, I hear ya...
[Laughter]
Pepe...
Huh?
[All gasp]
Oops.
They worship a goofy owl?
Halt!
Present-- arms!
"Crap in-- hand!"
Ready...
[Snickering]
Godo, are you ready to die?
"Uh, frankly, no."
[All gasp]
"'Tis a far, far better thing
I do than I have ever done."
Aim!
Uh-oh, it's the producer...
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank,
likes to crap in his hand ♪♪
Oh, I hope he doesn't see this.
[Trumpet fanfare]
Attention!
Sounds like pres'
and his horn section there.
Your excellency.
"Colonel Sanders,
what happened?"
"Well, there was a grease fire,
you know.
I had a little trouble
with the fries there."
And look, here's Peter noone!
Your excellency!
Police chief gebar's
acting on his own initiative.
I tried to stop him,
I tried to stop him...
"But he was all over me
like ugly on an ape!"
Release them!
Yes, your excellency!
Hey, who's that vector
on the stake--
John of arc?
Your excellency,
your excellency,
I request permission
to kill godo!
He mustn't be allowed
to go free!
He is our enemy!
"So, that's no, then, huh?"
Ooh...
"Monkeys... I hate 'em... uh."
Godo!
Johnny!
"I've missed you so!"
Godo!
Godo, don't die!
"Okay."
"You need to wash your hands."
It's gamera!
Oh, no, no, no, no...
Not really.
It's a kitchen lamp.
Johnny!
Please, he's just a little boy!
"I know."
Oh, please, don't hurt him!
Silence!
"Of the lambs."
Take him away!
No...
Oscar wilde?
To headquarters!
[Godo groans]
[Imitates groan]
Your excellency, your
excellency, you can't do this!
I have fought against godo
at the risk of my life!
Now that we have him,
he must be punished!
I request your permission
to kill him!
"On the other hand,
you're right of course.
Can I have a new desk?"
Your excellency!
Silence!
"Of the lambs!"
[Lisping]
It puts the lotion
on its skin...
[Siren wailing]
Meanwhile, on "c.H.I.M.P.S."--
[imitating siren]
Hey, it's a shriner.
"Hey, you kids behave
or I'll turn this plot around."
[Groans]
"Hey, he's not half-bad."
Your excellency,
please let the children go--
just the children.
Do not be afraid.
I will not harm you.
I do not hurt innocent people.
"I have assistants for that."
But if you cause trouble,
I will kill you.
Have you understood that?
"You will kill me!"
Yes, your excellency.
"This bites."
[Gasps]
Catherine!
Bethlehem... sort of.
[Siren wailing]
The king of the apes rides in
style in the new buick skylark.
He's got a monkey bar on it too.
Uh-oh, don't let those ramp apes
handle your luggage, guys.
Attention!
"Fling... crap!"
Oh, they're gonna give him
a 21-turd salute.
You know, they may have evolved
but they still have a lousy
paint job-- look at that.
Look at that car.
Get out!
[Fanfare playing]
[Imitating fanfare]
It's a masonic temple.
Yeah, we got
a special handshake.
[Groaning]
Oh, we better go.
[Sarcastically]
Sure wish we could
go with you, godo.
[All laughing]
♪♪
[Clears throat]
Hello, this is
our dramaticized pageant
of the scopes monkey trial
pivotal interpretation of law
which has a very thin connection
to today's film.
I'm your host, f. Lee Bailey.
Scene one, 1925,
Dayton, Tennessee.
John scopes taught the theory
of evolution in school.
This was against state law.
Man evolved from ape.
[Irish accent]
All right, you're under arrest.
Come with me,
tell it to the judge.
Thank you very much.
Scene two,
a sweltering courtroom
somewhere in Tennessee.
The question before the court:
Did man evolve from ape
or did man come from the Bible?
This is the plaintiff,
William Jennings Bryan,
played by our own Tommy servo.
Notice his resemblance
to fredric march.
[Southern accent]
Thank you.
Your honor--
um, he's not here yet.
Representing the defense,
Clarence darrow,
fictionally played
by Spencer Tracy,
recreated here by crow t. Robot.
Uh, I object.
Not yet.
Um, playing the part of
honorable judge Harry Morgan
will be this cardboard cutout of
judge wapner we got in the mail,
with the voice of me,
f. Lee Bailey.
[Whispers]
Okay, go.
Now, what's all this
horse hockey about man
evolving from monkeys?
Well, they did.
Uh, the defense rests.
- That's it?
- Yeah.
Well, that was
a very elegant, eloquent,
almost Oscar-winning
performance, Mr. Darrow.
Your honor and esteemed
colleagues of the bar--
- boring, boring.
- Shut up, crow!
Joel, tell him to stop!
Perhaps you ought to
cut to the chase, colonel.
Hey, I wanna be a colonel too--
that sounds neat.
Come on, you guys,
you're getting mired
in the boring subplot.
Joel, Joel,
where's the defendant?
Uh, she's still changing.
Oh, for crying out--
oh, there she is.
Man evolved from ape.
Yeah, but which man?
Yeah, what about women?
And what about
scarecrow's brain?
Uh, let's snap this up, people,
we're starting to lose 'em.
I find the plaintiff,
Mr. Scopes, you're guilty.
The fine is a thousand--
a hundred dollars.
Have this stamped by the bursar.
Shyster!
Hey...
And so the trial ends
in confusion-- neat, huh?
Oh, and Williams James Bryant
succumbed to the mortal strain
and died five days later.
Argh... oh... oh!
Clarence darrow went on
to greater things
like his role in "pat and Mike"
and the stunning "it's a mad,
mad, mad, mad world," then died.
Argh-- oop.
If you want to read
more about it,
ask your librarian
for the following books.
"Picture book of Tennessee,"
"welcome to the monkey house"
by Kurt vonnegut, Jr.,
the comic book version
of "planet of the apes,"
and "curious George
rides a bicycle."
[Buzzing]
We have movie sign.
Movie sign!
Oh...!
[Clanking, whirring,
creaking, whooshing]
Let go!
Fly, judgey, fly!
Whee-- there he goes.
Down in front!
Ooh!
No one can escape
from this cell.
"From now on,
your name is zippy."
[Laughing]
A little thumb-in-cheek
humor there-- very little.
[Groaning]
"Ooh, too many white castles
last night-- [retching]."
Aah! A bug zapper!
I checked in
but I can't check out!
Now get in there
and test that luggage-- ha!
What is this,
"planet of the fops"?
Now, remember-- if you are good,
no harm will come to you.
Understand?
Yes.
"Mmm... monkey eats."
"Mmm-- Reese's
peanut butter-- ow!"
We do not eat like barbarians.
You must show respect
for the customs of our country.
"Regurgitate, then eat."
First you thank the gods
before you sit.
Then you raise your food and
eat with dignity, understand?
"Then you do the hokey-pokey
and turn yourself around.
"That's what it's all about.
I'm outta here."
Oh, thank you, hanuman,
can we eat now?
"Let me see
if I've got this right.
You put your right shoe in and
your left shoe off and-- aw..."
Oh, no.
That never works.
[Groans]
Hey, he's making
linoleum angels.
♪♪
"Trick or treat for unicef."
This is when being a monkey
really comes in handy.
Are those monkey boys jeans
you're wearing?
No, he sat on a candy bar.
Oh, grate. [Chuckles]
You know, it's funny
how film directors
always make air vents
big enough to crawl through.
You know what he's afraid of?
He's afraid he's gonna
run into David hedison
going the other way.
Johnny, it's me!
Oh, pepe!
"Give a hoot, don't pollute."
[Suspenseful music]
[Imitating music]
Johnny--
"oh... oh, yeah, you gotta
lay off the pancakes, kid."
Ooh, hot pants!
Is there a screwdriver?
No, how about a bloody Mary?
Here's one.
Oh, I got it, pepe.
I always carry one.
Oh, great-- welcome to
"plot convenience playhouse."
♪ Pop music. ♪
Now, it's righty-tighty,
lefty-loosey.
Aw, Lucy, I need
a screwdriver, aah...
Okay, I can get through.
Be careful no one sees you.
I'll find godo and we'll
come back for you.
"Oh, Johnny, do you
need to be changed? Whew..."
I can get through too.
Everyone can get through
except for bulky Catherine.
You'd better stay
and you just pretend
I'm still inside the cell.
It's much safer.
"And it's fun too!"
"Bye-bye, keep in touch!
Scream if you get killed."
Tonight on "crime dog"...
[Panting and growling like dogs]
[Barking]
Don't strain yourself.
[Laughs]
That's great.
Godo!
"Am I on a wall? Oh."
No, it's impossible.
"Not unless I turn myself
into a boiled potato."
Veg-o-matic action.
Oh...
Far-out trails, man... ooh...
♪ You can tell by the way
I move my stuff,
I'm a woman's ape,
no time for talk. ♪
♪ Unh-unh-unh-unh,
stayin' erect, stayin' erect ♪
♪ unh-unh... ♪
He looks like
Teddy ruxpin up close.
"Simian night fever."
[Gasps]
Oh, stupid kid, don't do that!
♪♪
"So, you've been
to cost cutters again."
Godo! At last I have
lived to see the day
when I will kill you.
Well, it's nice to have goals.
It's taken a long time.
For years I have thought of
the pleasure it would give me.
"To move my jaw."
[Laughs]
This time you will not
escape me!
"That trick never works."
Very well, do just as you like.
I want to ask you one question.
"Is it okay to pet
on the first date?"
What'll you do with those three?
I don't know yet.
Tar? You're soaking in it.
Look at those hands.
Kill me, it doesn't matter.
Just let
those three humans alone.
"You can kill me, but it's
over my dead body!"
"You know, you still have
sausage links for fingers,
I don't care what you do."
Look, he's pointing
a duck call at him.
[Imitates duck call]
[Laughing evilly]
[Imitating laughter]
I'm asking you, let them go--
they are innocent!
Silence!
Wha... wha... wha...
Suddenly the film editor
goes for an Oscar.
[Grunting]
Try punching him.
No, harder.
Oh, it's a good thing
he got that boy off his back.
[Grunting]
"Bedtime for bonzo!
Come on, kids."
"Uh, I need to get
a drink of water, okay,
so just wait there."
Where are they,
Caroline and Catherine?
This way.
[Dramatic cymbal crash]
"Hey, who played that cymbal?!"
Someone's there!
"Can Johnny come out and play?"
[Chuckling]
Oh... it's just a kid.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
"Are you known for your work
in the theater?"
[Alarm burbling]
Godo's escaped!
Kill him!
It sounds like the alarm's
underwater.
Hey, apes, I think
your speaker's blown--
it's the woofer.
Oh, I get it-- they're gonna go
catch the "f" train.
[Imitating bouncy movie music]
Goin' uptown.
"We're gonna hide
in this jiffy lube stand."
Godo has escaped!
After him! Kill him!
"Ow, ow, ow, my fingers!
Ow, ooh, my fingers, ooh!"
You fools!
I told you
to behave yourselves--
didn't I tell you that?
Yes-- I'm very sorry.
You will regret your behavior.
"There will be more zooms
like this!"
- Major!
- Your excellency!
Find that boy!
I want godo and the boy alive!
If these three prisoners
are killed,
then they will be
worthless to us!
Yes, your excellency!
- Follow me!
- Yes, sir!
"I'm the boss-- pretty much."
You mean godo has run away too?
We will find him again.
Your excellency,
I don't care about my own life,
only the children.
They have done nothing,
they are innocent.
Let them go.
If you had not disobeyed
and followed my instructions,
things would be different.
"Not better, just different."
We'll wait till nightfall.
They might find us before then.
Oh, no, we've made it this far.
I'm starting to get hungry.
[Tires squeal]
- Cover all the exits!
- Yes, sir!
"Uh, your oil's done."
- Oh.
They must be here somewhere!
Johnny-- we'll get in the truck.
Yeah...
"I can see from here they need
a new oil filter though."
"Look, famous potatoes."
Okay.
Easy.
"Harder..."
[grunts]
Get in.
"I smell a rat--
oh, it's you, pepe."
"Hi, we'll be right back--
enjoy the film."
"Smells like a man and a little
boy in here-- who bathed?"
- "Not me."
- "Wasn't me, no way."
♪♪
[Imitates siren and music]
"You cried earlier, Carl--
you wanna talk about it?"
"Oh, cover your knees, honey--
I mean, sergeant."
"Come on, everybody."
Hmm?
♪♪
Oh, she's way overdue.
"Hey, I saw this in a three
stooges movie once, come on."
Nyuk-nyuk-nyuk.
[Imitates Woody Allen]
"It's-- I got a bad back--
it's this lumbar, it's out.
"He was--
gonna have to, uh-- oh....
I'll help you, here."
"You know, I thought
I smelled aqua velva."
"Later, when we're
off duty? Okay."
[Dramatic trumpet notes]
[Imitating notes]
[Whistling
"colonel bogey's march"]
"Hey, who's walking
on my bridge?"
We're far away.
How do we find
Caroline and Catherine?
"I found them quite pleasant,
and you?"
Where are they hiding?
Hey, how did he get his
opposable toe in that boot?
I tell you, I don't know.
Why do you insist
on protecting them?
After all, didn't they run away
and leave you here to die?
"Hey, good point-- give me
a banana, I'm joining you."
Isn't it? Then why haven't they
come for you?
"Uh, the lights
were against them?"
I'm sure they're going to
come back for us.
[Laughs]
It's not that funny.
♪♪
It's a Donovan video!
[Imitating Donovan]
♪ walking in the grass
with the sunlight in her hair ♪
Huh?
Oh, look out
for the floating pith helmet.
What the...
They're going to blow-dry
everyone now.
"Um, smile, please--
thank you.
"And now the junior class--
"And now the seniors--
thank you.
I'll have these back by the end
of the trip-- thank you."
Pepe, are you all right?
A little tired.
He's not pepe anymore.
We'll rest for a little bit.
I was wondering-- that flying
saucer seems to be everywhere,
like it was following us.
Mm-hmm.
Do you think there's a special
reason it's doing that?
Maybe to protect us.
"Yeah, we need it
for the third act."
Could be from a friendly planet.
"Maybe it's Ruth buzzi
and Jim nabors."
Why don't they try to signal us?
It's a mystery--
who do you think they are?
"Who do you think you are?
You look like
a hostess cupcake, pepe."
Pepe, are you okay now?
Yes.
All right, come.
"Ah, geez, kid,
you're sweating like a bear--
or should I say lemur?"
[Gasps]
No, no, I know
what he looks like.
He looks like a woodchuck
that got nailed by a splat ball.
Mm-hmm.
[Humming casually]
[Imitating massive gunfire]
Hey, what are you doing here?
"I'm a traitor to my species."
Your father is stationed here?
Yes, he's an officer.
"And a gentlemonkey."
Well, go on.
You shouldn't hang around here.
Goodbye-- nice meeting you.
There's some good security.
Is this Watergate?
Oh, there are guards everywhere!
"It's beautiful."
[Whoosh]
Why, that's Caroline!
"And her pneumatic drapery."
Is Catherine there too?
I don't know--
I couldn't get any closer.
"Didn't have any certs."
Here's the back door
to the building,
and they're in a room
on the second floor,
overlooking the yard.
But there are guards
posted all over.
"Is this to scale?"
Here is an emergency exit,
but we can't get to it unless
we use the outside stairs.
Godo?
Well, here's what we'll do.
"We'll bang our heads together
and walk around in a daze."
Today we've got three separate
views of love, monkey style.
[Godo]
--Load as much straw in it
as you can.
We'll meet back here.
"Just roll that cart around
for about eight hours,
then head back."
Then we'll try to get into
the back door of the building.
But you'll have to be careful
so the guards don't
suspect anything.
"Would you shut up back there?"
♪♪
Hmm, child labor-- neat.
[Whispers]
We're there.
[Johnny]
Pepe, you're terrific.
Hey, you there!
Godo, he's coming.
Okay.
What are you doing?
You can't leave that there.
I got tired.
Okay, I'll help you.
It's against regulations
to stay here.
"And I'm not a good soldier."
All right now, pull-- whoa!
Give him a rug burn!
Monkey pile!
Yay!
Monkey in a blanket.
- Pepe, keep watch.
- Right.
♪♪
That kid looks like roseanne.
Come on.
Is he gonna tell people
he spilled nair on his face?
Neil peart on drums.
He's still there.
♪ La-la-la-la... ♪
He should really learn
the lyrics to that.
Okay, now.
Hmm, kid talking to hay--
nothing wrong with that.
"See how I do that?"
[Rapid bass line]
♪ People try to put us d-down. ♪
Johnny, you wait there.
Mmm.
[Staccato organ music]
♪ Talk about--
pop music ♪
♪ everybody talkin' 'bout-- ♪
Sounds like
a lovin' spoonful song.
- It kinda does.
- The good time.
Ooh, he really
shocked the monkey.
Johnny, all clear-- come on.
The weather ball flashes green--
no plot foreseen.
"Howdy, ma'am, howdy."
[Staccato organ music]
Sounds like Johnny one-note
on his emenee magic key organ.
- "♪ Hello... ♪"
- "♪ hello... ♪"
"Where's the other guy?"
- Hello.
- Oh.
Prepare the plane for combat.
Can't it wait till tomorrow?
"We don't have planes--
we're apes."
Very well,
I'll see that it's done.
"Dickweed."
What, doesn't anybody have
peripheral vision in this movie?
I don't know.
Oh, there's a guard there.
Elite republican guard.
That's the room.
What do we do?
Little Johnny's got bags
under his eyes.
[Imitates whispering
and chuckling]
"That's dirty!"
[Whistling]
[Coughs]
"Hey, cover your mouth, kid."
What are you doing here?
Halt! Halt!
"Ooh, that's what you're
doing here.
Thank you, have a nice day,
thanks for shopping Walmart."
Let's go.
"This is the principal's office.
"They're showing that film we're
not supposed to see-- huh?"
It's me, Catherine!
"Your name is Catherine?"
Johnny!
"Huh?"
Johnny...
"Ooh, you smell
like a primate house."
- Catherine!
- Johnny!
"Now how about a little sugar
for godot?"
Godo, godo.
Catherine...
[Sobbing]
Ricky schroder in "the champ."
Johnny...
You're gnawing
on my arm, Johnny.
You're safe--
we were so worried.
"My hair's all wet."
Nice teeth.
"All done?"
Godo!
Let's hurry, we can talk later.
We have to get out of here.
Godo, there's no reason
to run away.
What?
The commander is very nice
and he said we were
under his protection.
His protection-- it sounds
like some kind of trap!
It must be.
We must get going.
No-- I'm staying.
No, you're coming with me!
Don't forget,
we saw traces of human beings.
They have to be near here
and we must try to find them.
Godo...
Yes, we'll all go together.
"Huh, who dubbed you?"
Caroline!
I want to find
other human beings!
Caroline, you saw
how he treated us.
The commander has been
very kind to us.
He's not like the others.
An ape is still an ape!
"An ape by any other name
would smell as bad."
We must get going!
Catherine, please, come with us.
Godo, I tell you it's the truth!
The commander was really
trying to protect us.
And I tell you
it must be a trick.
Come on, we're losing time.
Do something!
Come on, Caroline, hurry!
[Gunfire]
"The blue and the gray."
The apes of the old west.
That's John Wesley ape--
he once flung crap at a man
just for snoring too loud.
After them, after them!
Forward!
"Apes" is filmed
live on location
in deadwood, south Dakota.
We're surrounded!
They've got us!
Godo! Let's see you escape now!
Look, the flying saucer!
"Where?"
♪♪
From shootout to space-out.
[Gasps]
It's that flying saucer again!
Shoot it down!
Yes, sir!
Yeah, right.
"All right, men,
put your face diapers on!"
"Depends ready, sir.
Don't these go over
our red butts?"
Get ready to fire
the nuclear guns!
This time I'll show them-- fire!
[Zapping]
Doh... huh-huh, go figure.
Mine's gone too.
"These are no good."
Fire!
[Goofy laughter]
What are you waiting for?
Shoot it down!
It's "the wackiest war
in the Congo!"
"Mchale's Navy goes to
the planet of the apes!"
On today's matinee movie.
Hey, look, "caddyshack."
Oh, no, no, that's pepe.
Godo, look, a guard.
"No..."
"Can I borrow your styling gel?"
"Halt, who goes there?
"Who played Dr. Zaius
in 'planet of the apes'?
"That's wrong.
You're right."
[Twangy music]
Come on!
Well, it's about this time
that the old ape boys
got themselves into a heap o'
trouble over at cooter's place.
See, they were pickin' nits
off each other and, well--
Johnny, hurry!
Where'd they go?
"Well, they could be in one of
those trucks driving away."
Shoot them!
Shoot them, shoot them!
Our guns still aren't firing!
"Throw your guns at them!"
Johnny, what'd you do?
I took the key
from the truck-- there!
"That's our truck!"
Johnny, you're a pretty
smart guy.
"It's fun when you're smart!"
[Laughing]
Shall we wait
for the flying saucer?
Yes.
Gebar might catch up to us.
Zsa zsa gebar?
Oh, no, no, no, she's still
doing community service.
If we only knew
why they're following us.
Maybe they think
we're following them.
"Hey, that would be a switch."
I noticed it always comes
from the east.
Maybe they're trying
to follow the plot!
It's a little old devo hat!
Those spud boys are everywhere.
It looks like it's signaling.
- Yes.
- Well, let's go.
No, wait a second!
I'm beginning to understand now.
Unless I'm wrong,
the organization know as ucom
is now trying to take over
the ape country.
It wants us to leave.
Maybe they're getting ready
to attack.
Ucom has never attacked
human beings.
We should contact them
and seek their protection
or the apes'll get us.
It could be dangerous.
Shall we try it?
Anything to move the plot!
It's our only chance.
I'm for it!
[Chuckles]
"Yes! To our death, then! Whee!"
Careful! The command car
is approaching!
"Put those dice away
and get your roller skates on."
"Hey, where'd you get
the beamer, monkey dude?"
"I, uh, fell in a cow pie--
I hope nobody notices."
Stop him, stop him,
he can't come in here!
He's not the commander anymore!
Losar is our new leader!
We have orders
not to let him in!
"It's a madhouse!"
Let us through, let us through!
"Oswald's been shot!"
Don't let anybody in!
The commander is coming!
It's like trying to get
to the bathroom at a frat party.
How would you know?
"I'm with the band,
I'm okay, let me through."
The commander is here!
How dare you come in here?!
Keep 'em out, keep 'em out!
Oh, your excellency!
So, you have betrayed me.
Arrest him, arrest him!
Arrest him, I said!
Lower your weapons.
Check this out, this is good.
Ooh, really unfortunate skin.
You are too weak!
You protect our enemies!
We want to fight and kill
those invaders!
That is your plan?
Yes, it is.
I gave orders
to have them killed.
I give the orders here.
You are not
our commander anymore.
I'll give you one last chance
to call off this rebellion.
But your excellency...
And I give you my word of honor,
our enemies shall be punished.
Very well, your excellency.
Godo, where are we going?
"Do the words 'shallow grave'
mean anything to you?"
I'm taking you home.
"Home, where my thoughts
escape me?
Home, where I comb my facey?"
Aw, she's gonna be grounded
until she's 30.
It's a she?
Hmm...
Looks like she's been
rooting for tubers.
"Lassie!"
Mama!
Pepe! Oh! Pepe!
[Hooting like monkeys]
I was so worried about you.
I looked everywhere for you.
I even went
as far as green mountain!
Oh... but you're home now.
Excuse me, ma'am,
brawny wants his shirt back.
Pepe... I couldn't imagine
what had happened to you.
"I've become a man, mother."
"They are cute, but they smell."
Pepe, at first I even thought
that you were killed
by one of those naked apes.
"I even rented out your room."
Don't be afraid.
Pepe, pepe!
It's all right, mama,
these are my friends.
They're the ones
who saved my life.
"And they speak monkey!"
I've been traveling with them
a long time.
I can explain.
We were forced to take pepe.
I'm very sorry.
We didn't want to take her
along, but we had no choice.
We were being pursued by troops.
"That true, honey?"
I know how worried
you must have been.
Are you leaving me now?
Yes, to go back to our country.
You understand?
No, no, please,
take me with you!
Pepe, you have to stay
and take care of your mother.
I want to go with you.
Pepe, I envy you because
you found your mother again.
But I want to go with you!
Pepe, you have to stay
with your mother!
But i-- I want to go
with Johnny and Caroline.
Be quiet!
Do you want your mother
to be sad?
"Um... can I think about it?"
[Sad harmonica music]
Oh, it's toots thielemans
on the mouth harp.
Pepe, Johnny is right.
We'll see you again.
"Not."
Johnny!
Pepe... you must be a good girl
and stay here with your mother.
"Stay... stay, pepe."
"Sit... stay."
Pepe... you'll be all right?
"We'll get you a tick bath
and a rawhide chew."
Goodbye, pepe, goodbye!
Goodbye, Johnny!
I'll miss you!
Come back soon!
[All imitating gunfire
and screaming]
Should we have shot her
that many times?
Oh...
There's one good thing--
we met pepe.
I don't think
I'll ever forget her.
I don't think you'll ever get
the smell out of the seats,
either-- woof!
That's gebar's Jeep!
- He must be nearby.
- Yes.
"B.j.? Hawkeye?
Trapper John?"
I've been waiting for you, godo!
"I made snacks!
I hope you like pizza rolls!"
What do you want?
Don't worry, godo,
I've no soldiers.
It's just you and I.
I'm in a hurry.
I have no time for you today.
I have more urgent business.
When I've finished,
then I'll see you.
"Maybe brunch on Sunday?"
Silence!
"Well, we could reschedule.
Make an appointment with
my secretary or something."
I'm going to kill you!
I deserted my post and came here
just to kill you!
I must avenge
my wife and my son!
It's Don knotts in
"the shakiest ape in the west"!
I'll take care of gebar,
Catherine.
Take the children up to the
cliff and wait for me there.
Godo!
No, not pluto-- that's too far.
Godo, you can't escape now.
Come on out!
[Gun clicks]
[Gasps]
"Uh-oh..."
"Get back to the ponderosa
and tell hoss we're in trouble
and get me
some chicken-fried steak."
[Laughing]
Godo!
I've finally got my revenge!
You wanted to go
to green mountain
but instead you'll go
to your death!
[Laughing]
Gee, it's not that funny.
Listen to me-- your thirst
for revenge is against me!
But the other three are not
involved-- let them go free!
Oh, come on...
I can't believe the clothes
those guys are wearing.
"My name is Inigo Montoya!"
Godo-- now prepare to die!
[Laughs]
[Whooshing, creaking,
whirring, clanking]
--And the outlook for Friday,
more of the same.
Rain, rain, rain, rain, rain.
[Chuckles]
So, uh, it's a good idea
that we keep our scuba gear
for the next couple of days?
[Chuckling]
Over to you, Joel.
Thanks, Tom servo.
Anyway, up next is our
fashion editor, crow t. Robot,
with the fashion minute--
crow?
Thank you, Joel.
Hello, hello, hello!
This spring's ape is dashing,
daring and absolutely shameless
in paramilitary garb
as the house of primates
unveiled its Tarzan collection
to the dazzled designers
assembled in Milan,
and, oh-ho, lucky me,
I have the footage.
Uh, roll that footage, cambot.
Here comes ennui, patrolling
the byways of fashion
in a breezy street-length
heavy wool dress,
smartly accented by an orange
ascot with white shoulder bag
and matching belt.
Koko's a classic in this Chanel.
Shoulder pads, leggings
and jaunty gold buttons
put all eyes on this soldier.
Ten-hut!
Colors scream for attention
in these fun, fun, fun,
one-piece action jumpsuits
by dicker and dicker.
Although they can fly solo,
just add a broach, white lacquer
skullcap and jackboots
and you'll soar
to new fashion heights.
Back on the home front,
you'll wait for your king Kong
with this indigo print kerchief
by Dr. Zaia.
But hold onto it--
this little number's red-hot
and looks great on any species!
Halt, who goes there?!
Why, it's Jacques
in the timeless
colonel Sanders topcoat.
Noted the raised brass buttons
and velvet collar.
This ensemble makes any ape
king of his jungle.
Off duty? Then bivouac
in this oh-so-soft,
rich velour dinner jacket
from the Cornelius collection.
Just add a riding crop,
blue taffeta ascot,
and you'll be the cinderella
of any Liberty.
Attention, all personnel:
Incoming fashion!
Our military parade ends with
a salute to the medical corps.
These gauzy white linen
surgical masks breathe life
into any wardrobe.
One of this years
most versatile accessories,
the surgical mask doubles
as a red-butt cover.
Well, this is one reporter
who is ready to enlist
in any "gorilla" war
that looks this great,
so this year,
uncle Cornelius wants you!
Back to you, Joel.
This is crow--
bye-bye for now!
Around the earth in 30 minutes,
this is commercial sign.
♪♪
Oh, we have fun, don't we?
[Clicking]
"Darn lighter--
out of fluid."
[Flying saucer humming]
That flying saucer again!
Whoever you are up there...
Tell me, why do you prevent me
from carrying out justice?
He's doing a scene from "lear"!
--Killed my wife and son!
Yeah, yeah...
I must have my revenge!
You must have your valium too,
buddy-- calm down.
You must let me kill him!
Oh, that's how big it is.
Godo killed my wife and son!
He's waiting for godo, I think.
Godot.
Hey, it's the house on the rock.
You must let me kill godo!
Just let me do this one thing--
boy, that monkey sure can emote.
Just let me do this one thing.
[Computerized voice]
Ucom has ordered
that there should be a stop
to all further killing---
"or you will be killed."
But godo killed
my wife and my child!
He deserves to die!
Why do you want to save
godo's life?
- Huh?
Oh, you know the party's over
when they bring out
the vacation slides.
Absolutely-- I'm ready to go.
Help me, help me!
It's babu-- it's my son.
[All gasp]
Oh, I've seen this one.
Hold on, hold on.
Boy, the color is terrible--
think you can do something
about that?
Try to catch this-- oh!
"Oh, there's that rope
I used to have-- I've been
looking for that."
Oh...
Ooh!
You know, those two apes
probably never did
very good in gym.
They can't climb the ropes
at all.
Oh, he shouldn't have
shaved his mustache.
--I'll try to pull you up.
I can't hold on any longer!
Godo, try to save my son!
Save my son!
You know, in films,
this is where getting
final cut really pays off.
"Live, damn it, live!
Come on, you never gave up
on anything in your life--
now live..."
"Oh, boy, is my face red!"
That's not the only thing--
that's red.
Come on!
He's an ape and he can't
hang on to a rope?
Something's wrong.
A little more! There!
♪♪
"Godonko, come back!"
[Gunshot]
Oh, it's Earl Warren's
single-ape theory here.
Hello, there-- hope you've
enjoyed today's matinee movie.
My son... I killed my own son!
It wasn't godo--
I killed my own son!
"Hurts, don't it?
Bye..."
♪♪
[Gasping]
Geez...
[Sobbing]
[Imitates charlton heston]
"I did it, I finally did it...
Damn me all to hell!"
[Percussion instrument rattles]
Meanwhile, at the Ford falcon
with the vibraslap option--
it's the commander!
"Oh-- hang on, just a sec--
don't say anything yet--
wait, I gotta get this door--
okay."
"How much do I owe ya?
Told you not to come
by way of the expressway--
it's all torn up over there."
"Sorry, sorry, sorry."
"Hurry it up, I gotta do Lincoln
at the globe theater."
Your excellency,
ucom's been signaling us.
Be careful-- it must be a trap
to kill you.
But the flying saucer
always used to help us,
and it's an agent of ucom.
It's a trick!
[Gebar sobbing]
Gebar?
"Ho-ho-ho, I just heard
the funniest joke..."
Your excellency,
I don't deserve to live.
I've done a terrible thing.
I'm a murderer!
I've no right to live anymore.
I-- I killed my wife and my son.
What's that?
Yes, I killed
my wife and my son.
"Come again?"
"Geez, you are a sicko."
And I always thought
that godo had killed them.
Gebar, it was an accident.
You have a good heart--
"but you got really bad breath."
Oh, your excellency...
Gebar, it was an accident.
- K-Mart?
- The savings place?
- Oh...
- "I don't feel very good, i'm
gonna go rent 'faces of death.'"
godo... I accused you wrongly.
Please forgive me.
"Yeah, well, sorry don't feed
the bulldog, pal."
Oh...
"Oh, Lou, Lou..."
Oh, the poor thing--
to have to live with that.
"So, lunch, everyone?"
No, we're going to contact ucom.
You are being fooled.
You do not realize the dangers
that lie deep in green mountain.
Ucom can be very treacherous--
stay here with me.
Catherine, let's go.
Just a moment, please.
The rebellion is over.
We can have a peaceful life.
Let us go back together.
I can't.
I know that you have been kind.
Only we are human beings
and this is an ape country.
"And it stinks to high heaven."
Please understand.
"Think of the children."
Among strange creatures,
in a strange country,
away from our homes--
"a stranger in a strange land."
She's not gonna start to sing
"ebony and ivory," is she?
- No.
- I hope not.
Wait a minute,
it's Darren mcgavin.
I knew it.
"I'm hungry."
♪♪
"You really are different."
I understand.
Yes, because we are different,
you'd be afraid
to live among us.
But that will change soon.
One day, different people
will learn to live together--
message! This is the message!
Message, people, message.
I wish you well on your journey.
Thank you, sir.
I don't know how to express
our gratitude for all
you've done for us.
"How about a hickory farms
gift box?"
- Captain.
- Your excellency.
"A couple of those cigars
you have on your sleeve."
"Fruit is good, sir."
You might need this.
"Neat."
It's been a great pleasure
knowing you.
I hope you will think of us
once in a while.
"You know, when you drive past
a bloody raccoon on the side of
the road, that kind of thing."
Take good care of my friends.
"Um, I'd wash that hand
if I were you-- that's
my throwing hand-- yeah."
♪♪
Goodbye, goodbye.
"I gotta get this outfit
back to prince."
"I, uh, put a time bomb
in their car-- watch this."
Any of you guys
ever been to the dells?
This kinda reminds me of it.
You ride the ducks.
We're very close.
The entrance must be somewhere
behind the mountain.
Well, that's narrowing it down,
isn't it?
Look, there's the flying saucer!
[Mocking]
"There's the flying saucer"
[mocking in gibberish]
Well, put your thumbs out,
maybe you can hitch a ride.
Godo, where's it landing?
Behind that rock formation.
I don't know this place.
I wasn't allowed to play here
as a child.
Then ucom's certainly there.
Be careful.
Oh, look!
"It's a u-store-it!"
This must be the entrance.
How do we get in?
"Try knocking."
Again with the feet!
[Clicking and whooshing]
That was easy.
[Caroline gasps]
[Imitating gasps]
Well, let's go.
[Suspenseful trumpet notes]
Miles Davis is in there.
Beware of the balrog...
Isn't that from
"lord of the rings"?
We all of a sudden
have leather lace-up boots
and eight-sided dice?
Hey, give me a break.
You know, if you looked
at those lace-up boots,
I'd have to kill you?
Ooh.
[Whooshing]
Hmm... hmm... hmm?
This week only,
at the Omni theater...
The Joshua light show!
♪♪
[Catherine]
We must have come
into the future.
[Zapping]
Ooh, boy...
Are we in the left ventricle?
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank... ♪
"I'm Frances farmer!"
Johnny?
Nope, Catherine's vivien Leigh
and Johnny is John berryman now.
Fashions by issey miyake.
And it shows.
[Rattling doorknob]
That was easy.
Now she's on the inside.
Focus!
Please!
Hey, focus!
Hey, it's a scene
from "the miracle worker."
- La.
[Discordant jazz]
Oh, no, it's Anthony Braxton
and Don cherry, run-- no...!
It's very surreal.
[Gasps]
"Hi."
It's William Conrad
for first alert!
[Alarm blaring]
Catherine...!
[Imitating alarm]
This is like
an obsession commercial.
"If I'm an ape,
then pronounce me guilty."
"Between apes and men...
Lies obsession."
I thought I'd lost you...
[Mocking echo]
Lost you... lost you...
Lost you...
Caroline!
Run like a duck!
[Imitates quacking]
Caroline!
She passed out from
the sheer length of the film.
Caroline, Caroline!
Uh, she was awake
about ten slaps ago.
"My brother lives in Florida."
Catherine!
Caroline!
[Imitating giddy laughter]
You know where Johnny is?
"Do you know where
Buffy and cissy are?"
We're still in the ape country!
I just saw apes!
Caroline, calm yourself.
I saw apes, Catherine!
Calm down, Caroline.
I did see them, I did!
They're coming,
they're coming after us!
We'll talk to their leader,
the commander.
Catherine!
James Bond.
[Hums bond theme]
Catherine!
Hey, it's the guys from
"clockwork orange," the droogs.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, no, no, no, I think it's
a group of Castro impersonators.
♪♪
Please don't hurt us!
Don't hurt us!
Huh?
They seem to be
in a state of shock.
Uh, so are we.
[Gasping]
[Mocking gasping]
Our mystery guest is...
Who's that?
Dr. Lee!
[Gasps]
[Organ playing]
Welcome back home.
"The music is goofy here too."
We're back where we started!
Catherine!
[Mocking gasping]
Any more gasping and we're gonna
run out of air in this room.
"Aah! It's an ape!"
Doctor, they've had
quite an experience.
I don't think they'll forget it
for a long time.
- Yes.
- "That oughta teach 'em."
[Gasps]
And now, part two
of "time of the apes."
Dr. Lee,
where are the other two?
Hmm, two?
Yes, Johnny and--
Johnny is over there.
We put the three of you
in different rooms.
But we were four.
The third capsule was empty.
No, it can't be!
Godo was with us, a young man!
Face it, sister,
he blew you off.
You must have had
some kind of hallucination.
The capsule is still here?
It's in the laboratory,
the door on the right.
"Take it out for a test drive.
I gotta get back
to the meat counter."
Catherine!
Run like a duck again!
[Machines beeping]
"I swear he was in
one of these."
Oh!
Godo's a pendant?
Maybe he's in there.
Catherine!
He "in de pendant."
[Laughs]
Sorry.
"Uh, your loan's been approved."
Roseanne!
- Mother!
Johnny!
"Hey, buddy! Buddy, buddy boy!
Where are my goldfish?"
It's so good to be back.
Johnny.
I never thought
I'd see you again.
"We were hoping."
"It's done--
turn up the voltage, Hank."
[Imitates electricity zapping]
Well, that was really good,
let's get going.
Yeah, let's get out of here.
I liked that one.
That was fun,
that was really cool.
What?
Hey, wait a minute.
It's still on?
Oh, for crying out loud.
Seven days?
Fortunately, only a limited area
was damaged--
how many endings
are we gonna get?
The rescue team
worked around the clock.
It still took seven days
to dig you out.
Only seven days?
In may.
You've had an incredible
adventure, I know,
but time is relative.
"You mean, like my dad?"
No one will believe that your
experience of six months
only lasted seven days.
But it's the truth!
"Yeah, right."
[Blowing raspberry]
I know it's the truth
and I have evidence.
- Mm-hmm?
- Yeah?
I have data that corroborates
your story.
He's now working
for "Star Trek."
I noticed certain deviations
in the time scale.
It shows 3.714 years.
"Yeah, I can see it."
And the thermometer shows
an incredibly low temperature.
"Neat."
We thought 273 degrees below
zero was the lowest temperature,
but these readings indicate--
"um, are you calling me frigid?"
And that could have
elongated the time scale.
Hell, it's a shot anyway--
let's just end this thing.
Dr. Lee, the capsule was in
such a low temperature zone--
hmm...
Where the universal
computer was.
Hmm...
- Hmm.
- Mm-hmm.
Hey, isn't this scene
like closing the barn doors
after the cows are out?
I understand now--
it's all very clear.
- It's smoking.
- It's a big joke for people
who are high!
You reversed into the past.
[Whispers]
Keep stretching...
But there was another factor.
Extremely low temperature, which
caused the time scale to warp,
and therefore
the deep freeze capsule
acted as a time converter.
Oh... this movie's even stupider
than I thought it was.
Oh, godo...
Oh, what happened to him?
He enjoys long walks on
the beach at his Malibu retreat.
He must have taken a wrong turn
at Albuquerque.
Hmm...
Well, that's the sand.
Catherine, there's something
I'd like to ask you.
Me too.
I know what it is.
You want to ask me about godo.
"No-- why does my ice cream
taste like a burger
and why are we now little kids?"
It's not easy to explain.
We came back
to where we started--
we returned to the present.
Mm-hmm?
Godo had a different journey.
He's in another time zone.
Did he go to the past
or the future?
Where do you think he is?
"I'm my own grandfather!"
I don't think we'll ever know.
Hmm?
"So, more ice cream?"
But one thing I do know,
and I know for certain.
Godo, wherever he is now,
he'll always be in our hearts.
[Children]
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes, definitely.
In our hearts.
"We'll always forget him
forever."
Oh, is there gonna be
another ending now?
Hey!
Yay!
♪♪
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank,
gads about the house all day ♪♪
♪♪
[Whooshing, creaking,
whirring, clanking]
Come on, everybody,
let's do the Sandy frank song!
♪♪
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank ♪
♪ he's the source
of all our pain ♪
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank ♪
♪ gads about the house all day ♪
♪ thinks that people
come from trees ♪
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank ♪
♪ gets horrid movies
from Japan ♪
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank ♪
♪ then they're always
poorly dubbed ♪
♪ Sandy frank, Sandy frank ♪
♪ Spielberg won't return
his calls... ♪
Sir, uh, better check this out.
They're gadding about again.
Oh, for heaven's sake,
we don't have time
for this kind of nonsense.
Don't you have a letter to read?
And quit camping it up
up there-- babies are sleeping.
Oh, yeah, we could read the
letter, I don't see anything
wrong with that, do you?
Well, this letter we picked out
is from a guy--
well, I'll just read it to you.
Let's put that
on still store, cambot.
It says, "dear Joel,
crow and Tom servo,
"my name is Vladimir Lopez,
I'm 15 years old
and a devoted fan of mst3000.
"It is my absolute numero uno
a-1 favorite show.
"I live in Tijuana, Mexico,
and never miss a show.
"I just love everything
about it,
"especially the songs and
plays you come up with
during the breaks.
"However there's
one part I hate,
"and that is when the mad
scientists push the button.
I wish it would go on longer."
We too.
And then he added
a really cool---
oh, now, that's cool.
Let's put that up there, cambot.
Good work, Vladimir!
Let's tell 'em about the mst
information club, Tom servo.
All right-- send your letters
or anything else you can
fit in a mailbox to:
Do it today.
I don't think
you should have said
that thing about the mailbox.
What do you think, sirs?
Uh, I'd better
push the button, sir.
You better change him.
Uh, tell you what, frank.
I changed him the last time.
I'll push the button
and you change him.
Well, I always push the button.
I know, and i--
you shouldn't have to.
I'll push the button this time.
No, it's fine, I'll do it,
don't worry about it.
You go ahead and change him,
I'll push the button.
No, I think you should
have this experience.
You can change him
so you'll know--
oh, I'll push the button.
[Frank]
His first words!
♪♪
Johnny, don't go,
it's too dangerous.
I don't care!